Guide to the Donald J. Fluke Papers, 1958-1988
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Donald J. Fluke papers 1958-1988
University Archives, Duke University
Fluke, Donald J.
2.1 Linear Feet 800 Items
Donald J. Fluke was a professor in Duke's Zoology Department.
His collection includes correspondence and other documents relating to the Zoology Department, the Graduate School, research proposals and safety, and faculty involvement in civil rights activism. Materials range in date from [1958]-[1988].
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Donald J. Fluke Papers were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 2001.
Biographical Note
Donald Fluke was born in 1923 in Nankin, OH. He received his B.S. from Wooster College in 1947, his M.S. from Yale University in 1948 and his Ph.D. from Yale University in 1950. He joined the Duke Zoology faculty as Associate Professor in 1958 and became chair of the department in 1969, where he studied the effects of radiation on animal cells. He chaired the Academic Council from 1969-1971, was Faculty Secretary, and was actively involved in Duke's plans to found a residential college. He is now (2006) professor emeritus in the Biology Department.
Collection Overview
Contains correspondence, memoranda, printed materials, clippings, minutes and other records of several University committees from the years roughly 1958-1988. Also includes documents and correspondence relating to research proposals and permits. Major subjects include the Duke Radiation Safety Committee, the Founders' Day Committee and the design of the University Medal, the origins of the School of Business, the Zoology Department, and the Aeolian Organ. Collection also includes documents relating to faculty participation in the civil rights and other Vietnam-era activism.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Aeolian Organ.
Duke University. Dept. of Biology.
Duke University. Duke Radiation Safety Committee.
Duke University -- Faculty -- Political activity.
Duke University. Founders' Day Committee.
Duke University -- Zoology Dept.--Faculty.
Fluke, Donald J.
Related Material
Department of Zoology Records, 1905-1997.
University Archives, Duke University.
Gray (Irving E.) Papers, 1915-1980.
University Archives, Duke University.
Gross (Paul M.) Papers, 1939-1979.
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 1 Boxes
  - Duke Aeolian, 1988- (Box 1)
  - May 1970 Vietnam, etc.
  - Duke / Special Historical 1960. Vigil 1967 [1968]
  - Duke / Special Historical 1960. Vigil 1967 [1968]
  - Klopfer and related
  - Biophysics Plans at Duke, Old and New, History Prior to 1958
  - Biophysics Committee
  - Faculty Age Structure and Retirement
  - Graduate School of Business Administration, 1968
  - Fellow, Trinity College [1965-1967]
  - Founders' Day Committee, 1986-
  - Isotope License 32-6655-14 (E62)
  - Radionuclide Use Permit. [and related materials concerning waste disposal and a loss of radioactive material, 1960]
  - Duke University Radiation Safety Committee, 1960-[1984]